Ryan M. Allen

rmallen09@yahoo.com

719-239-0607

0

3838 Steelhead St. #12B, Fort Collins, CO 80528

RESUME OBJECTIVE

Data Science graduate student with 6+ years of math teaching experience and in the top 17% of teachers in North Carolina seeking entry-level or junior Data Scientist positions. Effective communicator with a keen ability to break down complex mathematic concepts into manageable pieces and adept at data analysis and decision-making. Experienced at creating data regression models, using predictive data modeling, and visualizing data through R, RStudio, ggplot, and R Markdown. Also, with exposure to Python, SQL, and text analytics.

TECHNICAL AND SOFT SKILLS

R | R Studio | Markdown | Python Predictive Analytics | Machine Learning Leadership

Data Visualization | Data Analysis Handling Pressure Collaboration Problem-Solving

Motivational in a challenging environment Self-Starter Quick Learner Results-Oriented

Google Analytics Certified Exposure to SQL Attention to Detail Adaptable

EDUCATION

M.S. Data Science B.S. Ma

Regis University, Denver, CO | 2019 **B.S. Mathematics**

Colorado Christian University, Lakewood, CO | 2012 **B.S.** Business Administration

Colorado Christian University, Lakewood, CO | 2012

EXPERIENCE

MATH **T**EACHER

LOVELAND HIGH SCHOOL, CO FEB. 2018 – PRESENT

MATH TEACHER

AC REYNOLDS HS, NC Aug. 2014 – June 2017 MATH TEACHER

ADAMS CITY HS, CO Aug. 2013 – Aug. 2014 MATH TEACHER

McGinnis MS, CO July 2012 – Aug. 2013

RESPONSIBILITIES AND ACCOMPLISMENTS

- Effectively communicated with parents, principals, coaches and students, both verbally and written
- Created core curriculum, researched and performed best teacher practices
- Top 17% of Math III teachers in North Carolina according to growth
- Data-driven implementation of curriculum based on assessments
- Results-oriented, state and national test results drive instruction
- Teaching/motivating 100+ students daily
- Taught Linear functions, regression, randomization tests, geometric principles, polynomials, quadratics
- Co-Teacher and a member of a Professional Learning Community
- Fostered Relationships with students, peers, and stakeholders
- Instilled a problem-solving mindset in my students
- Continually pushed math teaching boundaries looking for newer, better, more advanced methods to drive instruction farther and increase engagement and understanding
- Earned two degrees in 3 years
- Working full time and enrolled full time in graduate data science studies
- Google Analytics Certified

<u>LinkedIn Profile</u> <u>RPubs Profile</u> <u>GitHub Profile</u>